Vishwanath Biradar (Industrial Designer/Digital modeler)

Address:: C/o JOHN. S. SERRAO

SAGAR PLAZA APT RM-21 FLT NO-27

G- BLOCK MIDC SAMBAJI NAGAR PUNE- 411019

E-mail: vishwa.birs@gmail.com

Mobile: +91 7387342518 | 8660229979

Summary

Overall 4 years of experience in Design , NPD, Quality control, Project management, Application Engineer for various GOM software's in various platforms like R&D, Automotive, Aerospace, Transportation, Power Generation, Home appliance, Sheet Metal forming, Medical technology, Design studio's and handling complex projects, exposure to wide variety of manufacturing processes from basic fabrication to high volume tooling.

Education

09/2016-2018 - NTTF PG School, Bangalore- Karnataka

Masters in product Design and Engineering

2008 - 2012 - Shree Devi Institute of Technology, Mangalore (VTU, Belguam)

B.E Mechanical Engineering

2006-2008 - M.V High school & Jr. college Umadi (Kolhapur board-Maharashtra)

PUC/+2 -Science

Work Experience

15-05-2018 - PRESENT

Pune - Maharashtra

3D MAGIC INFO SOLUTION Pvt .Ltd- Position: post graduate trainee Engineer/Digital modeller

- 3D magic is the design studio where they assist complete product life cycle from concept phase to
 Design, develolopment, manufacturing testing and validation of product.
 Services offered-automotive styling (cas and class A), Engineering design, CAE& Simulation , prototyping
 3D scanning and reverse engineering , Tool & Die Design , fixture and spm.
- Working with Industrial Design team and studio facility at 3D Magic.
- Associated with project team throughout the product development cycle.
- Handling from sketch stage to CAS Delivery.
- Can take research activity to investigate and promote new product ideas /concept.
- Working with engineering teams to interpret requirements and translate them into optimal design product
- Industry experience with ICEM SURF.
- Good understanding model making 3D scanning, prototyping.



- Automotive interior and exterior, CAS, class A using Alias
- Class A Surfacing from scan with Icem surf.
- 3D Scan data handling like aligning modified some portion of vehicle with existing data, reducing the data keeping same quality for ease of handling file.
- Reverse engineering,
- Worked various OEM's for class-A surfacing.

17-03-2016 - 30-08-2016

Pune - Maharashtra

FORCE MOTORS - Position: Engineer, Centralised Tool Room Dept.

- New Development of body parts for p2 project with vendors/suppliers.
- Directly involved taking corrective action for quality improvement.
- Reverse engineering of sheet metal, plastic and casting parts for p2 project.
- Redevelopment of existing very old dies, inserts parts, fixture, components.
- Actively participated in centralized Tool Room Quality Dept. for measurement of various parts, sub assemblies, assemblies ranging from 50 mm to 50 Meter.
- Measurement done for dies, fixtures, sheet metal parts, machined critical parts, checking fixtures and gauges.
- Hands on experience for various GOM software's like ATOS Professional, Gom inspect, Photogrammetriy.
- Making various kind of documents for quality reporting like R&R, CP CPK.
- Trained my Manager and colleagues in Gom software and made aware of it to other department to take maximum utilization of the gom system .
- Working with various departments for special requirement and achieving successful results.
- Closely worked with R&D for Redesign and development of imported parts.
- Used various instruments for measurement like Vernier, Micrometer, Bore Gauge, plug gauges, slip gauges steflemayer cmm.
- Making 3D inspection reports by using scan data v/s CAD data in Gom software.
- Measured "KARAMAN" body cubing fixture by PHOTOGRAMMETRY and the length of the fixture was 50M.
- Preparing and sharing lessons learned during the project execution.

07-04-2014 – 03-03-2015

03-03-2015 - 16-03-2016

New Delhi

Pune- Maharashtra

APM TECHNOLOGYIES - Position: Quality/Application Engineer

- APM Technology is a GOM 3D Metrology product & GEs Industrial CT scanner authorized distributor
 and service provider in the field of new product development, reverse engineering 3D Printing for
 almost all R&Ds, DRDO, IITs, AIIMS DELHI, Wind & hydro Power plants, all OEMs like GE, Maruti Suzuki,
 M&M, Tata, Bharat Forge, GM, HAL, BHEL, Honda, VW, Bajaj, Ford Motor, ESCORT, L&T,JCB, Godrej, ZF
 etc.
- GOM 3D Metrology products are used for 3D measurement, QC Analysis, Material testing for automotive sheet metal components, 3D, 2D & GD&T Measurement and benchmarking of automotive as well as all possible type of products/parts including Aircrafts, Submarine, Medical equipment and power equipments.

- Bench marking of cars (more than 25 cars from BMW 7 to Honda city), bike agricultural equipments, and medical equipments for cost reduction.
- New product developed in DC Design Pune for Hummer, scania, Honda city, swift, Mercedes van.
- Closely associated with DC Design team for Building Mobile Jewelry store on SCANIA Truck.
- Closely associated with DC Design team for sharukh khan's Vanity van.
- Worked for DC'S sports car AVANTI for the development.
- Very closely associated with DC Design Team for interior and exterior modification of vehicles for several projects.
- Scanned premature baby faces (more than 25) at AIIMS DELHI for respiratory new product development and closely worked with IIT Delhi Team for the same.
- Scanned fractured Thai bone and reproduced through 3D printing at IIT BOMBAY.
- Developed more ergonomic special scissor for Doctors to perform long hour operations at IITB
- Scanned and redesigned Russian made MI17 choppers to fit the Indian surveillance system and relocate fuel tank for honorable prime minister of India through DRDO.
- Scanned and 3D Inspected stretching tools for aircraft wings through HAL Kanpur.
- Scanned and 3D inspected nuclear-powered ballistic missile submarine –INS Arihant built by SBC VIZAG.
- Demonstrating the GOM metrology equipments to various industries like Automotive, aviation, Energy, shipbuilding, Educational institutes, R&D, Medical Home appliances etc.
- Demonstrating GOM's static deformation equipment for steel manufacturers.
- Provided training to the various domain customers for Gom metrology products.
- Solving customer's quarries regarding 3D inspection from GOM software.
- Installation and up gradation ATOS software.
- GD &T Inspection using GOM software.
- Given technical talk on Mutual assembly and demonstrated the same, it was not topic in the conference held at Kolhapur.
- Mutual assembly for core assembly analysis through GOM Optical Measuring Technology. This exercise saved huge amount of material in foundry.
- Associated with JHONE DEER team for converting metal into plastic parts for HOOD and coual.
- Worked for new product development with JCB supplier from clay to production.
- Closely worked with Johnson control for new product development of seats and plastic parts.
- Closely worked with MAGNA for new product development of plastic parts and seats with foam.
- Associated with Godrej home appliance team for development of plastic parts.

14-07-2012 - 01-04-2014

Chakan, Pune - Maharashtra

Aditya Automation – position: Quality/Project Engineer

- ADITYA AUTOMATION is a designing, manufacturing and commissioning of jigs, fixtures conveyors, spms, Assembly lines, precision machine components and gauges. In my service projects done for these customers like Daimler, GM, Carraro India, AES, Bruckner India, TAL, M&M, Siemens, Tata Motors, Godrej, Bajaj Auto, Caterpillar, L & T, Hirotec, FIAL, Swaraj Tractors, etc.
- 16t& 7t main line assembly fixtures Daimler Chennai.
- Packsys Global Machine Components (Brukner) Switzerland.

- Inspection of fixtures, dies, gauges with Faro arm and Romer Arm.
- Cart (engine hot testing) for GENERAL MOTORS.
- SPM with PLC operated for swaraj tractors.
- Developed low cost 1000 bearings for BAJAJ played key role from selecting material to inspection of the same.
- Worked for More than 45 assembly and welding fixtures made for Swarai Tractor.
- Closely associated for making spm to fill the grease for seating assembly.

Others

- Completed internship in Engine System at Continental Automotive India, (Bangalore)
- One day Visit to CIPET Mysore.
- Attended 2 days training on INDUSTRY 4.0 and Industrial IOT. Organized by AICTE New Delhi. At RV College Bangalore.
- Attended several exhibitions and Conferences.
- TVS Motors Alias training for one week(two wheeler rear fender scan to surface in alias)
- Completed Paulson plastic material course.

Technical Knowledge/skill set

Product Design | Ergonomics | New product development | GD&T ,Tol stack up | 3D scanning | 3D Printing | Mechatronics | Tooling and Gauging | NPD | TRIZ | QFD | DFMA | Advance Manufacturing process | Reverse Engineering | Packaging & feasibility study | Benchmarking .

Extracurricular Activities

- Given technical talk on Gom inspection software and its application in automotive industry in automotive industry ranging from concept to production.
- Participated in International GOM Education award (GERMANY).
- Designed and Developed working THERMOCAL CUTTING MACHINE in Design Studio.
- FOAM modeled of own concept SUV.

Software Knowledge / Computer Proficiency

Packages: surface modelling: Icem surf | Autodesk Alias | Rhinoceros |

3D Modelling: | Creo | CATIA V5 | Ugnx | AutoCAD | | Mesh mixture | | Imageware | | Geomagic

Rendering: |Luxion KeyShot | Photoshop | Illustrator |

3D scanning Inspection: GOM 3D SCAN | **ATOS** Professional | Photogrammetry | Delcam Power Inspect |

Faro Gage | PCDMIS | CMM

Personal Traits

Can do attitude | flexible | good listener | confident | goal oriented | punctual | willing to take up challenges and responsibilities | International mindset | work with international customers | continuous improvement mindset.

Personal Profile

Name : Vishwanath BiradarFather's name : Shamarao Biradar

Gender : MaleDate of birth : 05-06-1989

Languages known : English, Hindi, Marathi, kannada.

Marital status : SingleNationality : IndianPassport number : L8711857

Hobbies : Planting trees, yoga, Spiritual reading

Permanent Address : S/o Shamarao Biradar, At Alaginal, Post: Ghonsagi

Tal/Dist: vijayapur-586114.

Declaration

I hereby declare that the above written particulars are true to the best of my knowledge.

Place: Pune Signature
Date: (Vishwanath)